Guide to the Barbara Howes Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Barbara Howes papers
1914-1995
YCAL MSS 59
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
27.34
(33 boxes)
The Barbara Howes papers contain writings, correspondence, personal and financial papers, and photographs documenting the life and literary career of American poet and editor Barbara Howes. The collection includes extensive files on all of Howes's book-length publications and many manuscripts and typescripts of individual poems, short stories and articles; her correspondence with her family, particularly with her mother and her husband, the poet William Jay Smith; and letters from a wide circle of literary friends and colleagues, including Leonie Adams, Elizabeth Bishop, Malcolm Cowley, Denise Levertov, James Merrill, W. S. Merwin, Katherine Anne Porter, Theodore Roethke, and Richard Wilbur.
Howes, Barbara, 1914-1996
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Series I-IV purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Dwight and Nathan funds, 2002. Series V is the gift of Barbara Howes, 1960-1966.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 33 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Barbara Howes (1914-1996)
Barbara Howes (1914-1996) was born in New York and adopted by Mr. and Mrs.Osborn Howes, Jr.of Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts. She was raised there and educated at Beaver Country Day School; she graduated from Bennington College in 1937. After working briefly for the Southern Tenant Farmers Union in Mississippi, she moved to Greenwich Village and began submitting her poems to literary magazines.
From 1943 until 1947 she was editor of Chimera, with David Newton and Ximena de Angulo. A "little magazine," the journal published poetry by John Berryman, Richard Eberhart, Randall Jarrell, Kenneth Patchen, and others, as well as articles by such authors as Carl Jung, Thomas Mann, and Henry Miller.
Howes published seven collections of poetry: The Undersea Farmer (1948); In the Cold Country (1954); Light and Dark (1959); Looking Up at Leaves (1966); The Blue Garden (1977); A Private Signal: Poems New and Selected (1977); and Moving (1983). The Collectted Poems of Barbara Howes, 1945-1990 was published in 1995.
In addition, Howes also edited the anthologies From the Green Antilles: Writings of the Caribbean (1966) and The Eye of the Heart: Short Stories from Latin America (1970).
She married the poet William Jay Smith in 1947, and they lived for a time in England and Italy before settling in Vermont. They had two sons, Gregory Jay Smith and David Smith. The couple divorced in the mid-1960s, and thereafter Howes lived mostly a secluded life on her farm in Pownal, Vermont. Barbara Howes died in Bennington, Vermont in February, 1996.
Scope and Contents
The Barbara Howes papers contain writings, correspondence, personal and financial papers, and photographs documenting the life and literary career of American poet and editor Barbara Howes. The collection includes extensive files on all of Howes' book-length publications and many manuscripts and typescripts of individual poems, short stories and articles; her correspondence with her family, particularly with her mother and her husband, the poet William Jay Smith; and letters from a wide circle of literary friends and colleagues, including Leonie Adams, Elizabeth Bishop, Malcolm Cowley, Denise Levertov, James Merrill, W. S. Merwin, Katherine Anne Porter, Theodore Roethke, and Richard Wilbur.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, 1929-1991. II. Correspondence, 1922-1995. III. Personal and Financial Papers, 1914-1995. IV. Photographs, 1916-1957.V. 1960-1966 Gifts of Barbara Howes Writings, 1959-1965..
Chimera; American literature -- 20th Century; American literature -- Women authors; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Women authors; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Adams, Léonie, 1899-1988; Bishop, Elizabeth, 1911-1979; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989; Howes, Barbara, 1914-1996; Levertov, Denise, 1923-1997; Merrill, James, 1926-1995; Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1927-; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980; Roethke, Theodore, 1908-1963; Smith, William Jay, 1918-2015; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017
- Writings, 1929-1991; Series I; 13.67; (14 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of Barbara Howes' writings, along with proofs and correspondence files related to particular works and publications. In addition to files on all of Howes' book-length publications, the series also contains information on her early unpublished writings and on individual poems, stories and articles.
  Most folder titles have been taken from the original folders and/or from appraisal and dealer information; most folder contents notes have been taken from the same sources.
  Correspondents represented here often also appear in Series II, Correspondence.
  - Original poetry manuscripts and publisher correspondence, 1950-1980 (Box 1)
    One large portfolio of early worksheets for poems and ideas for poems and letters of acceptance or rejection from various literary magazines.
    Includes correspondence from Kart Shapiro, Howard Moss, John Ciardi, Peter Davison, Norman Holmes Pearson, Henry Rago, Daniel Halpern, and Grace Schulman.
  - In the Cold Country, typescript, 1954 (Box 1)
  - "Adam and Noble: A Book for Children," unpublished manuscript, undated (Box 1)
  - Early poem scrapbook, undated (Box 1)
    Scrapbook folio of very early poems by Barbara Howes, all handwritten with some drawings and watercolors.
  - A Private Signal, typescript and typescript with corrections, [1954]; 2 (Box 1)
  - Cold Wave, manuscripts with corrections, undated; 5 (Box 1)
  - "Poems," portfolio of early worksheets for poems with corrections, ideas for poems and notes, undated (Box 1)
  - "On Walking a Dog," typescript prose manuscript, undated (Box 1)
  - Eye of the Heart, correspondence, 1973; 5 (Box 2)
    One large group of correspondence about Latin American short story anthology, including reviews, publicity, reader response.
    Includes correspondence from Alastair Reid, Susanna Rudge, Maria Luisa Bombal, S. J. Levine, Tom Goddard, Selden Rodman, Lysander Kemp, Bill Grossman, Donald Yates, Mark Strand, Oscar Aranjo, John C. Davidson, Dinah Silviera de Queiroz, Juan Bosch, Efinor Randall, Marco Denevi, Diane Giddis, John Schaffner.
  - "Cold Wave," autograph manuscript notes for poems and summary of "Cold Wave" (unpublished short novel) (Box 2)
  - "On William P. Dudley," typescript, circa 1940; 2 (Box 2)
    Typewritten manuscript regarding Howes' first meeting with her birth father, William P. Dudley in Exeter, New Hampshire on June 6, 1940. Also includes correspondence with Dudley.
  - Childhood writings, 1929 (Box 2)
    One folder of early writings from grade school: short stories, two examination books from 1929, a short story entitled "The Adventurers," as well as a six-page packet of cartoon-like pencil drawings and five pages of typewritten nonsense poems by Edward Lear.
  - "Canadian Travels," typescript about Barbara Howes' mother's Canadian travels, undated (Box 2)
  - Journal writings, 1986-1990 (Box 2)
  - "Form in Poetry," typescript essay with typescript poetry, undated (Box 2)
  - "On Louise Bogan," notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Publications including Howes works, undated; 2 (Box 2)
  - "The Road Commissioner," artists' proofs and silkscreen prints, 1983 (Box 2)
  - "Contemporary Author Series", autobiographical writings and page proofs from Gale Research's Contemporary Author s Series, undated (Box 2)
  - Atkins, Stuart: The French Text of Eleven Letters from Heine to His Wife (1844), offprint of an essay signed by the author, undated (Box 2)
  - "New Poems 1977--," typescript, circa 1977 (Box 2)
  - "Here Tomorrow," autograph manuscript outline for a play in two acts, undated (Box 2)
  - Poem manuscripts, undated (Box 2)
    21 original poem manuscripts, including holograph first, second and third drafts, with some consisting of eight to ten pages each.
    Poems included in this folder include "E Pur Si Muove," "Sitting Around Travelling," "Super-Inferno: Pittsfield-July," "For All Occasions," "To Fido, His Horse," "Repeating Values," "Mock-Natural Things," "Isolation Ward/ County Hospital," "All Clear By Satellite," ''The Clear Eyes of Toby," "English," "The Union of Art and Medicine," "Being Me," "Among Shells," "Dyed-In-the-Wool," "On His Life," "Sperar Temere ... ," "The Architect for H.K.A," "Sunset on Manasota Key," "Sheriff Peacher's Stockade," "Squares," and "The Fourth Step."
  - "Monkey Wrench," by Crystal Cunard (alias of Barbara Howes) with cover letter from Colliers, undated (Box 2)
  - Clipboard poems, undated (Box 2)
    Barbara Howes' writing clipboard on which she wrote nearly all of her poems and still contains handwritten drafts for poems which were never completed
  - Eye of the Heart, correspondence, 1971 (Box 2)
    Included are correspondence and signed agreement statements from many writers including Elizabeth Bishop, Juan Bosch, Lysander Kemp, Miguel Angel Asturias, Mario Vargas Uosa, Pablo Neruda, Alastair Reid, Frank MacShane, Jorge Amado, Biot Weinberger, Helen Lane, Daniel Halpern and many others, plus copies of correspondence from Howes to Juan Bosch and many others.
  - "Katherine Anne Porter," notes, undated (Box 2)
    Loose notes about Katherine Anne Porter taken by B. H. during phone conversations with Porter over the years, mostly handwritten but some typed. Includes an telegram from Porter regarding a short story, "Holiday." Folder also includes various newspaper clippings of interviews with Porter.
  - Notebooks on writings, undated (Box 2)
  - Poems, autograph and typescript manuscripts, undated (Box 3)
    Poems included in this folder include "The Blueberry Barrens," "A Letter," "Regina Coeli," "Play of Light," "The Mirror," "A Parable," "Man with Violin," "For Stewart Park," "For Genoveva Forrest de Sastre and for Kitty Genovese," "Casualinas for Louise Bogan," "Pride's Crossing," "Time," "The Sixth Color of the Afternoon" among others.
  - Private Signal: New and Selected Poems, reviews, [1977] (Box 3)
    Includes a letter from Charles Guenther and Frank MacShane, with a typescript of "Hollins Critic" piece on Barbara Howes by F. M.
  - "North Adams State reading" comments, undated (Box 3)
  - "Recent Poems," manuscripts, [1974] (Box 3)
    Includes T. Bjornvig poem translated by William Jay Smith and L. Sjoberg (with worksheets), William Jay Smith: op-ed article "Moscow Fur Hats", Richard Wilbur "Clerihews for Barbara Howes' Birthday'' (1974, signed), Barbara Howes: copy of letters to Eudora Welty, Miller Williams and Jacques Barzun, two letters from William Maxwell, one letter from Frank MacShane.
  - "Translations of modern Hungarian poetry," manuscripts, undated (Box 3)
    Includes letter from Miklos Vajda, editor of the "Hungarian Quarterly," Barbara Howes' translations of and worksheets of poems by J. Tornas and Zsuzsa Rakovsky.
  - "The New Calliope Singers", 1985 (Box 3)
    Settings for three of Barbara Howes' poems to music by Susan Hurley (signed): "Looking Up at Leaves," "Leaning Into Light" and " ____[?], St. Peter's Church, New York, May 3, 1985." Includes letter from Susan Hurley asking permission for setting
  - The Eye of the Heart, correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
  - "Literary Bits and Pieces", undated (Box 3)
    Including the manuscript of a review of Howes' work by Fred Chappell and Howes' notes for readings with comments.
  - The Road Commissioner and Other Stories, correspondence from Frederick Morgan and Ann Stanford of Stinehour Press, 1983; 3 (Box 3)
  - A Private Signal, correspondence, circa 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Eye of the Heart, correspondence, 1970s (Box 3)
  - From the Green Antilles, correspondence, 1960s (Box 3)
  - "The Blueberry Barrens", 1960s; 3 (Box 3)
  - "Isolation Ward", undated (Box 3)
  - "Looking up at Leaves," correspondence, 1966 (Box 3)
  - "Turning Point", undated (Box 3)
  - Moving, correspondence, undated (Box 3)
  - The Road Commissioner, undated; 3 (Box 3)
  - A Private Signal, extra copies and reviews, 1977; 2 (Box 3)
  - "Autobiographical Study," for Gale Research, typescripts and correspondence, 1980s; 4 (Box 3)
  - "New Calliope Singers," poems set to music by Susan Hurley, undated (Box 3)
  - Lists of Christmas poems, undated (Box 3)
  - "Oh Jamie", undated (Box 3)
  - Poems and prose, undated (Box 3)
  - "Outlines of film scripts," manuscript outlines of "Anniversary of Death" and "Lady in Waiting", 1950 (Box 3)
    Includes correspondence with Countess de la Fere (acting as agent in London)
  - In the Cold Country, correspondence, [1954] (Box 3)
    Includes letter from Andrew Imbrie
  - A Private Signal, reactions from publishers, [1954] (Box 3)
  - Light and Dark, correspondence and comments on individual pieces by J. V. Cunningham, [1959] (Box 3)
  - "Extra Copies," printed poems and reviews, undated (Box 3)
  - "Notes on Lectures and Conversations," notes on Bernard Berenson's conversations, plus her notes on Edith Sitwell, undated (Box 3)
  - Cold Wave, correspondence, 1950 (Box 3)
    One folder of correspondence from literary agent Diarmend Russell re: novel "Cold Wave" (unpublished), plus a letter from Hubert Creekmore dated 9/6/1950.
  - Italian and French translations of Barbara Howes' poetry, by Antonio Saffi (into Italian) and Jean F. Briere (into French), undated (Box 3)
  - The Eye of the Heart, correspondence, [1973]; 4 (Box 3)
    Includes correspondence from Norman Thomas di Giovanni, Oriana Radner, Selden Rodman, Hardie St. Martin, Fred Dupee, Jorge Edwards, Robert Mezey, plus correspondence from Willis Barnstone, Miller Williams, Lysander Kemp, Edouard Roditi, Edwin Honig, William Grossman.
  - Lists, undated (Box 4)
  - "Poetry Anthology - Ideas & Poems", undated (Box 4)
  - The Road Commissioner, corrected typescript with correspondence from Jordan Davies, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Moving, literary correspondence, 1983 (Box 4)
    Includes letters from Harvey Simmons and Dana Gioia, a copy of the agreement with Elysian Press, Robert Phillips' comments on the book, plus Howes' letters to Dana Gioia.
  - "Adam and Noble," correspondence unpublished children's story (about a dog) with comments from various publishers, undated (Box 4)
  - From the Green Antilles, literary correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 4)
  - "The Blue Garden," literary correspondence, 1972 (Box 4)
    Includes letters from Robert Penn Warren with comments on Howes' poetry, plus correspondence and agreements with Wesleyan University Press
  - "Adam and Noble," typescript drafts and comments from publishers, undated (Box 4)
  - Light and Dark, correspondence, 1959 (Box 4)
    Includes agreements with Wesleyan University Press, typescript sheets for contents, one manuscript poem, contracts, copyrights and editorial correspondence, Howes' description of the book, plus correspondence with W. Lockwood and Milton Saul
  - Twenty-three Modern Stories anthology, typescript of Howes' introduction with corrections, 1963 (Box 4)
    Also includes correspondence with John Schaffner and Hubert Creekmore.
  - "Italian anthology, poems, notes" (Box 4)
  - "An Eclectic Anthology," proposal for "Talking to Animals: an Eclectic Anthology", undated (Box 4)
  - "On American Poetry," typescript with corrections from collection of Howard Nemerov (from lectures on "Voice of America"), undated (Box 4)
  - "The Sea-Green Horse," short story anthology, permission slips and possible selections, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Looking up at Leaves, agreements and correspondence, 1966 (Box 4)
    Agreements with Knopf publishers; correspondence with Judith Jones, including letters from Milton Saul; Seymour Lawrence and Margaret Mitchell.
  - Poetry typescripts with corrections, undated (Box 4)
  - "Louise Bogan," commentary on the poetry of Louise Bogan, with reviews of Howes' work by Bogan, undated (Box 4)
  - "A Private Signal," literary correspondence, 1977 (Box 4)
    Includes correspondence from Walker Percy, Nona Balakian, Anthony Ostroff, Stephen Berg, Charles Guenther and Donald Stanford.
  - Poetry typescripts, undated (Box 4)
    One group of poems submitted to Houghton Mifflin for a poetry prize..
  - Twenty Three Modern Stories, typescripts and correspondence (Box 4)
  - The Blue Garden, literary correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    Includes correspondence from Alfred Com, Allen Tate, Frank MacShane, Norman Holmes Pearson, Roy Basler, Edwin Honig, Manny Weisbuch, Mitton Saul, Babette Deutsch, Marie Bullock
  - From the Green Antilles, permissions, 1966 (Box 4)
  - From the Sea-Green Horse, reviews: Nona Balakian ( New York Times ); Booklist; Library Journal, etc., 1970; 2 (Box 4)
  - "Form In Poetry," typescript (photocopy) and other literary materials, undated (Box 4)
    Including articles such as Willlam Maguire writing on Cary F. Baynes and Barbara Howes writing on Louise Bogan.
  - The Blue Garden, literary correspondence, undated (Box 4)
    Includes correspondence from Robert Penn Warren (plus framed and signed R.P.W. comment), as well as two pages of notes on manuscript by Charlee Wilbur.
  - From the Green Antilles, reviews and letters from Harriet de Onis, plus jacket copy of the book, 1966 (Box 4)
  - "Adam and Noble," typescript (Box 4)
  - "An Anthology for Boys and Girls," notes and ideas (Box 4)
  - Road Commissioner, typescripts and proofs, 1983; 4 (Box 5)
  - Looking up at Leaves, author's proofs, 1966 (Box 5)
  - From the Green Antilles: Writings from the Caribbean, original manuscript layouts, early manuscripts and correspondence, galleys, permissionsm and reviews, 1966; 6 (Box 5)
  - Poetry manuscripts, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - Eye of the Heart: Short Stories from Latin America: incomplete set of original manuscripts and complete manuscript, 1973; 2 (Box 5)
  - "The Yankee Tradition," typescript carbon, undated (Box 6)
  - From the Green Antilles, 3 (Box 6)
  - The Road Commissioner, print proof (Box 6)
  - From the Green Antilles, typescripts and print proofs, 4 (Box 6)
  - Christmas cards and poems, incoming (Box 6)
    Includes Christmas cards/poems from: Eudora Welty; Louise Bogan; Theodore Roethke; Stephen Spender; William Jay Smith; Maurice English; Claude Fredericks; "Poem for Greg's birthday" by Richard Wilbur, Lewis Turco; John Holmes; Robert Francis; Ned O'Gorman; William Meredith; John Frederick Nims; Kit and Ilsa Barker; Richard Wilbur, Norman Holmes Pearson; "Epithalamion" (Ruthven Todd); R. W. Stallman; Malcolm Cowley; William Jay Smith; James Broughton; plus various Christmas and occasional (e.g. W. H. Auden's birthday) poems by Barbara Howes and William Jay Smith, plus miscellaneous announcements.
  - "Millefleur," broadside poem, undated (Box 6)
  - "The Blueberry Barrens," broadside poem, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Christmas poems, outgoing, 1956-1991; 9 (Box 6)
    Includes: "Otis" (1968, two copies one signed); "Talking to Animals" (1969); "Regina Coeli" (1972); "Wild Geese Flying'' (1966); "Evening: Crown Point"(1971); ''The Sixth Color of the Afternoon"; "Hubert Walking- A Profile" (two copies); "For Mother: A Log" (for her 60th birthday 2/11/68; two copies); Christmas cards from WJS all signed; "A Liking for People and Animals (Homage to Helen) (1966, two copies); "Returning to Stone Bay" (1970, two copies); "A Christmas Poem: A Parable" (1975, two copies); "Gulls" (1964); "Looking up at Leaves" (1963); "Two poems" (1962); ''The Snow Hole" ( 1960); ''Two Poems by William Jay Smith" (1959); "Ugnum Vitae" (1956); "Elm-Burning" (1967); ''Two Poems" (BHS & WJS, 1948); "Poem" (BHS & WJS, 1949); Christmas card (Daumier print) (signed by BHS, 1951); "Old Man on the Isthmus" (1984); "Landscape and Figure"; "Annunciation"; "In a Prospect of Flowers"; "Montsenat A Watercolor" (two copies, 1984); "A Christmas Poem" (1978); "Sitting Around Traveling" (1960); "A Christmas Poem: A Point of View" (for Cary) (three copies, two signed, undated); "An Epithalamion" (for Petie and Frank Palmer, 21 June 1964); ''To W. H. Auden on his 50th Birthday" (1957); "For Helen and Bob Allen" (May 16, 1970); ''Together" (1991); "Older" (1990); Morning-glory" (1985); "At Pigeon Point, Tobago" (1986); "Quilt of an Old Pattern" (1988); "Early Supper" (1956); "A Christmas Poem: Man with Violin" (1976, two copies, one signed); "Christmas Poems" (1973) "Entrance" by Gregory Jay Smith and "Cara---- sp?" by Barbara Howes; "Christmas Poems" (1974) ("Reason" by Gregory Jay Smith and "Pride's Cousins"[?] by Barbara Howes (one signed by both, one signed by GJS).
  - "Night Voyages," printed in Whispers, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Light and Dark, advance proof, corrected, 1959 (Box 7)
  - The Blue Garden, advance proof, corrected, 1972 (Box 7)
  - "Odds and Ends," translations of Paul Valery and Gerard de Nerval, undated (Box 7)
  - Poetry readings, lists and publicity, [1957] (Box 7)
    Introductions to various poetry readings at Williams College and in Florence, Italy in 1957. Includes worksheets for her poem "L'lle du Levant: The Nudist Colony"
  - Nickerson, Gretchen: "The Shadows Are Deep," poetry manuscript and correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Poetry worksheets, undated (Box 7)
    Includes "A Point of View -for Cary;" ''The Backyard -for Cary;" "Sheriff Peacham's Stockade-for E.S.M.;" "Barn Raising in Pownal;" "2nd Wind;" "Cricket Raft;" "Manhattan -Thurs. 3 p.m." etc.
  - "An Autobiographical Study," typescript, undated (Box 7)
  - Journal pages, 1991 May - November (Box 7)
  - Christmas poems, printed copies, undated (Box 7)
    Includes "Myself;" "Being Me;" "Quilt of an Old Pattern" and "Among Shells"
  - [Untitled,] manuscript of early childhood novel: "Chapter One - Strange Footprints," "Chapter Two - Pete's Story", undated (Box 7)
  - Poetry worksheets, undated (Box 7)
    Includes manuscripts and worksheets for the following poems: "Filmed in Nepal;" "Older;" "Polly's Dream;" "Carnival Night," "At Pigeon Point, Tobago;" "The Dawdle Lag;" "Quilt of an Old Pattern;" "Isolation Ward;" "A Poem for July;" "Montserrat A Watercolor"
  - "Jazz Poem," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 7)
  - Collected Poems, correspondence with LSU Press, undated (Box 7)
  - "Looking up at Leaves," prospectus correspondence with the Press at Colorado College regarding broadside publication, undated (Box 7)
  - Clipboard with poem typescripts and manuscripts (Box 7)
  - "Daily Notes," journal writings from the last several years of Howes' life, 3 (Box 7)
  - "River Painter," by Emily Grosholz, typescript copy, inscribed to Howes (Box 7)
  - Chimera, bound set in two volumes, 1946-1948; 2 (Box 7)
  - "R.P.W. - Selected Poems," comments by Howes on Robert Penn Warren's "Selected Poems", undated (Box 8)
  - The Road Commissioner, letter to Stinehour Press, 1982 December 6 (Box 8)
  - Political writings and The Washington Spectator, 1982-1984, 1982-1984, undated (Box 8)
  - Eye of the Heart, correspondence about rights (Box 8)
  - Eye of the Heart, typescripts, corrected, 1973 (Box 8)
  - "Notes for New Poems," autograph manuscript notes, undated (Box 8)
  - "Current Work," early versions of short stories and poems: typescript with corrections, some autograph manuscript sheets, undated; 2 (Box 8)
  - Mt. Holyoke College reading, notes, 1984 April 27 (Box 8)
  - "Poetry Comments for Classes," loose notes, undated (Box 8)
  - Poems, original worksheets, manuscript and typescript drafts, undated (Box 8)